Guide to the Native American Educational Services Sol Tax Papers 1908-1993
University of Chicago Library
- Series XI: Newberry Library
  Series XI contains mostly publications from the Newberry Library related to Native Americans. These are almost entirely publications acquired by Sol Tax for research. This series has been arranged alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - Center for History of the American Indian, Occasional Paper Series, 1976-1981 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - D'Arcy McNickle Center for the History of the American Indian, Occasional Paper Series, conference papers, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous bulletins, advertisements, reports, and correspondence, A-Ce, 1977-1981 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous bulletins, advertisements, reports, and correspondence, Ch-U, 1972-1988 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - A Newberry Newsletter, numbers 1-4, 6-21, 23-26, 28-35, 1973-1992 (Box 28, Folder 5)
- Series XII: Newsletters and Newspapers
  Series XII contains newspapers and newsletters published by or about Native Americans. The majority of the series is made up of Midwestern newsletters, but other publications are from other areas of the country. This series has been arranged alphabetically and then chronologically.
  - AIC (American Indian Center), The Voice, volumes 1-8, 1983 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Human Relations News of Chicago, 1966-1968 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Indian Times, October 1969-July 1970 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Legislative Review, Volume 1, Numbers 1, 4, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Review, Volume 1, Number 5, January 1972; Volume 2, Number 1, November 1972 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Menominee News, 1957-1959 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous newspapers, 1965-1975 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - The Native Nevadan, 1968-1974 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - The Native Nevadan, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - The Native Nevadan, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - The Native Nevadan, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - The Native Nevadan, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - The Native Nevadan, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - The Native Nevadan, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - The Native Nevadan, 1981-1982 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - The NCAI (National Congress of American Indians) Bulletin, November 1958-November 1961 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Project Concern, newsletters, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Wassaja, November 1973-December 1974 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Wassaja, January 1975-August 1983 (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Series XIII: Social Issues
  Series XIII contains materials mostly unrelated to Native Americans. It represents Dr. Tax's interests in other areas of social concern, especially education and race and ethnicity. It is composed almost entirely of articles and reports about various social issues, as well as conference summaries and some correspondence. This series has been divided into four subseries to distinguish general areas of interest.
  Subseries 1: Community Development, contains materials related to urban growth and renewal, especially in the Chicago area. This includes many journal publications and reports and conference summaries for various community development projects.
  Subseries 2: Education, contains primarily publications and reports on educational strategies and education as it relates civil rights issue, especially desegregation.
  Subseries 3: Poverty, contains publications on economic issues and the "War on Poverty." It contains primarily publications from various authors on issues of poverty and racial divides.
  Subseries 4: Race and Ethnicity, contains correspondence and publications on topics of race, especially in American urban environments. It also contains a series of scholarly debates over the topic of the existence and importance of race.
  - Subseries 1: Community Development
    - Bibliographic guide, The Literature of Community Development, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Conference," Delivery Systems – What Kind of Model and What Are Its Implications," conference papers, April 21, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Conference, "Short Term and Emergency Measures to Avert Urban Violence," conference papers, November 13-14, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - General reports, budgets, and discussion of community development, 1964-1968 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Folder1: General reports, budgets, and discussion of community development, 1968 (Box 32)
    - General reports, budgets, and discussion of community development, 1968-1976 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Hyde Park-Kenwood, newspaper, renewal plans, drafts of reports, 1964-1968 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Rural Life Studies – Culture of a Contemporary Rural Community, numbers 3-6, 1942-1943 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Urban Development, reports and articles, 1963-1964 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Urban Development, reports and articles, 1965-1966 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Urban Development, reports and articles, 1966-1967 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Urban Development, reports and articles, 1967 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Urban Development, reports and articles, 1967-1969 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Publications, miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Publications, miscellaneous, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Publications, miscellaneous, 1965-1968 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Publications, 1991 Chicago Urban League Annual Report, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Publications, Agency for International Development, Community Development Abstracts, no date (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Publications, Beck, Ariadne P., and Norton B. Knopf, Final Report on the Training Program for Chicago Area Employment Service Counselors, November 1967-May 1968, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Publications, Beck, John M., Irving H. Cutler, and John J. L. Hobgood, Pembroke Township – A Research Report on Problems and Possibilities, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Publications, Institute for Community Development, Social Scientists View Poverty as a Social Problem, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Publications, Institute for Planning and Development, Urban Renewal – Social Surveys, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Publications, Jones, J.A., Report of the "Variables Influencing Behavior" Project, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Publications, Mobilization for Youth, Synopsis of Programs, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Publications, National Planning Association, Development Digest, 1966 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Publications, Research Center in Economic Development and Cultural Change, A Report to the Committee on Economic Growth Social Science Research Council, 1952 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Publications, Research Center of the Florence Heller Graduate School for Advanced Studies in Social Welfare, Brandeis University, The Middle-Income Negro Family Faces Urban Renewal, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Publications, UNESCO, Evaluating Development Projects, 1959 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Publications, United States Bureau of the Census, Current Population Reports – "Social and Economic Characteristics of the Population in Metropolitan and Nonmetropolitan Areas – 1970 and 1960," 1971 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Publications, Welfare Council of Metropolitan Chicago, Social Service Directory – Metropolitan Chicago, 1966 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Publications, The World Institute Council, Fields Within Fields Within Fields, 1973-1974 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Subseries 2: Education
    - Education and Anthropology, part 1, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Education and Anthropology, part 2, 1954 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Education and Anthropology, part 3, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Education for the Disadvantaged, bibliography, surveys, 1965-1968 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Education for the Disadvantaged, bibliography, surveys, newsletters and reports, 1965-1968 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Education for the Disadvantaged, brochures, reports, article drafts, 1966-1967 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - General, reports, article drafts, 1959-1962 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - General, reports, article drafts, 1963-1967 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - General, reports, article drafts, 1968-1975 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Minorities and education, brochures, newspaper article photocopies, notes, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Paper draft, "Communication Barriers to the Culturally Deprived," 1966 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Project Headstart, articles, newsletters, 1961-1965 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Project Headstart, articles, newsletters, 1965-1968 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Publications, Center for Applied Linguistics, of Projects and Activities in Reading and English, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Publications, Forbes, Jack D., Education of the Culturally Different – A Multi-Cultural Approach, 1966 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Publications, Guba, Egon G., Methodological Strategies for Educational Change, 1965 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Publications, Herbert, John, and John Swayze, Wireless Observation, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Publications, The NDEA National Institute Conference, New Curricular Materials and the Teaching of the Disadvantaged, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Publications, "The New York Review of Books," 1968 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Publications, The Rockefeller Foundation, The Long Road to College – A Summer of Opportunity, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Publications, School Management – Practical Solutions to School Management Problems, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Publications, Science and Freedom – Freedom and Efficiency – Problems of University Administration in Britain and the Commonwealth, 1960 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Publications, Southwest Cooperative Educational Laboratory, Ethnics on Education, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Publications, United Stated Commission on Civil Rights, 1964 Staff Report – Public Education, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Publications, United States Commission on Civil Rights, Education Parks – Appraisals of Plans to Improve Educational Quality and Desegregate the Schools, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Publications, United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, A Chance for Change – New School Programs for the Disadvantaged, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Publications, United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, Improving English Skills of Culturally Different Youth, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Strategies for Educational Change (SEC) Newsletter, 1965-1968 (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Publications and publicity materials, 1964-1993 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 3: Poverty
    - Reports, article drafts, 1953-1957 (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - War on Poverty, publications and publicity materials, A-C, 1966-1968 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - War on Poverty, publications and publicity materials, E-L, 1964-1968 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - War on Poverty, publications and publicity materials, O, 1964-1967 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - War on Poverty, publications and publicity materials, P-Y, 1964-1967 (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Publications and publicity materials, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 4: Race and Ethnicity
    - Black students at the University of Chicago, reports and correspondence, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, addresses, and newspapers, A-N, 1964-1974 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, addresses, and newspapers, N-U, 1962-1968 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Publications and publicity materials, A-Ch, 1961-1993 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Publications and publicity materials, Ci-Co, 1961-1968 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Publications and publicity materials, Fa-I, 1962-1969 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Publications and publicity materials, L-N, 1964-1968 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Publications and publicity materials, P-U, 1960-1985 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Publications and publicity materials, U-W, 1947-1966 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Publications, Boeschenstein, Harold, et al., The University and World Affairs, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Publications, Committee on Education, Training and Research in Race Relations of the University of Chicago, of Research in Racial and Cultural Relations, 1952 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Publications, Committee on Education, Training and Research in Race Relations of the University of Chicago, of Research in Racial and Cultural Relations, 1953 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Publications, Institute of International Studies, University of California, Berkeley, Asia Studies, Courses and Research, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Publications, Institute of Social and Economic Research, University College of the West Indies, Jamaica, Social and Economic Studies, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Publications, Inter-American Studies at the University of Florida, Gainesville, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Publications, Pakistan Planning Commission, A Report on Assistance by the Ford Foundation and Harvard University, Design for Pakistan, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Publications, Philippine Studies Program, Department of Anthropology, University of Chicago, The Chinese Community of Manila – A Study of Adaptation of Chinese Familism to the Philippine Environment, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Publications, Sewell, W.R. Derrick and Gilbert F. White, The Lower Mekong, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Publications, Social Sciences Today, Editorial Office, USSR Academy of Sciences, Against Racialism, 1971 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Publications, United States Commission on Civil Rights, Law Enforcement – A Report on Equal Protection in the South, 1965 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Publications, United States Commission on Civil Rights, Racial Isolation in the Public Schools, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Publications, United States Commission on Civil Rights, Survey of School Desegregation in the Southern and Border States, 1966 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Publications, United States Commission on Civil Rights, Voting in Mississippi, 1965 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Publications, Thomas, Brinley, International Migration and Economic Development, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 7)
- Series XIV: Oversized
  Series XIV contains materials that have been separated from other series and relocated due to their size. There are several maps and large negative plates of the Fox Project's documentary history.
  - University of Chicago Department of Anthropology, "The North Americans," population distribution maps, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Kenneth, Philip R., Ed., Indian Self-rule – First Hand Accounts of Indian-White Relations from Roosevelt to Reagan, print draft, 1985 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Documentary History of the Fox Project, negative plates of the second version, no date (Box 43, Folder 3)